## Krénusz Bence

### **Data Scientist / Machine Learning Engineer**

bence.krenusz@gmail.com

### **Skills**

#### **Data Science**

Over two years of Machine Learning experience I have gained heuristic knowledge regarding the End to End Machine Learning process flow. The technical implementation was achieved mainly by Structural Python Programming, however the knowledge of the R language was required to support the work of my Team Mermbers. At the earlier period my responsibility was to build up mostly Decision Tree based models (DT, RandomForest) for classification and regression. And to build Clustering models using different distance matrixes (Euclidean,Gower,etc...). After I have dived deeply into Deep Learning, I have built up several Neural Network model. In the latest period I have mostly focused on my Deep Convolutional Neural Network model based on Inception Network for Image recognition and Video analytics.

#### **Process Automation**

It was my responsibility to find the State of the art Automation solution for the End to End Machine Learning process, hence I gained insight into the current best solution for every individual usecase. We have tried several options (Microsoft ML Studio via Logic App, Azure Automation Developement App, Azure DataBricks, Windows Task Scheduler, etc..). In a lot of case the more simple ideas fit the best (e.g. To embed the Machine Learning process directly after Data Engineering process inside of SQL Agent).

#### **Data Engineering and Business Intelligence**

Working closely with the Data Engineer and Data Analyst colleagues in a small team I have gained visibility on the processes beyond Machine Learning (e.g. ETL and SSIS; Power BI and Tableau). From the Cloud to the On-Premises solutions, We have walked through the possibilities to find the best fit for our usecases from the Data Engineering point of view. Regarding the Business Intelligence, it was part of my job to gain experience in different BI apps, where I got familiar with the logic of querys and custom visualizations. Due to my Python and R knowledge, the embedded script features in these platforms made this process easier.

# **Tools**

- Python
- R
- Azure Databricks
- Microsoft Power BI
- Tableau
- MSSQL
- PyCharm
- Visual Studio
- AutoCAD

# Libraries

- Numpy
- Pandas
- SqlAlcemy
- Matplotlib
- Seaborn
- Plotly
- ScikitLearn
- Tensorflow
- Keras

# **Experience**

### **Nokia - Data Scientist / Machine Learning Engineer**

#### From 1st of June 2018

Leading the techincal solution (of Python programming) to solve Business problems such as Predicting Supply Chain Delivery variables and Sales Opportunity information to optimise Resources and Sales Outcome. Responsible for the End to End Automation solution for the Machine Learning Environment. Support the project which Predicting Demand information as Data Science assistant. Support the Analytics Community with Deep Machine Learning and Python programming knowledge.

#### **Udemy, Kaggle - Data Science Preparation**

#### Feb 2018 - Jun 2018

I have completed the Python programming for Data Science course on Udemy, which was in perfect connection with my previous Python knowledge. I did dive deep into the specified libraries of Python (Numpy, Pandas, Seaborn, Matplotlib, Scikit Learn) which was required to became a Data Scientist. In addition I have looked into the R programming language, and started to gain knowledge. When I have recieved my certificate I have turned my direction to the Kaggle competition platform, where I have faced myself with Online Competition challenges. House Prices titled world competition for Data Scientists: It was a Regression problem. My job was to predict the sales price for each house in the test dataset. For each Id in the test set, I must had to predict the value of the SalePrice variable. Right after I have started to seek for Data Scientist positions to find my required Business challanges.

### IT Services Hungary Kft. - System Admin/Data Analyst

Jun 2016 - Feb 2018

In addition to my daily responsibilities i have started to learn Python programming by myself. I have explored the main logic of the language and the different programming styles. I have completed an exercise series which gave me the required knowledge to take an advanced course.

#### Evosec Kft. - Camera/Fire alarm installer

Sep 2015 - Sep 2016

## **Education**

### **Udemy Academy**

#### **Data Science Certification**

Topics of the Course: Programming with Python NumPy with Python Using pandas Data Frames to solve complex tasks Use pandas to handle Excel Files Web scraping with python Connect Python to SQL Use matplotlib and seaborn for data visualizations Use plotly for interactive visualizations Machine Learning with SciKit Learn, including: Linear Regression K Nearest Neighbors K Means Clustering Decision Trees Random Forests Natural Language Processing Neural Nets and Deep Learning Support Vector Machines

## Óbuda University, Donát Bánki Faculty of Mechanical Engineering

**Mechanical Engineering Degree (Bsc)** 

2013-2017

### **Eötvös Loránd University**

**Matematics and Physics Studies** 

2011-2013

## **Hobbies**

Currently focusing on a wide areas of sports. After 8 years of Judo I have started to do more independent sports such as climbing, tennis, squash, skiing, swimming and street workout. In addition I really like to hike and bike.

Bence Krénusz | bence.krenusz@gmail.com